Guide to the George Platt Lynes Scrapbooks
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Scrapbooks, ca. 1900-55; Series I; 4.94; (4 boxes)
  - VOLUME II
    - Pages 63-76 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      70-71: [Removed items: Photographs -
      Set illustrations by Pavel
      72-74: [Removed items: Photographs -
      Costume illustrations by Pavel
      75: Woman with oxen; boy with camera
      boy cadets
      76: [Removed item: Colored clipping -
      Nude girl carrying camera, with
      separate decorative pasted over as
      border]
    - Pages 77-86 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      77: Czar Nicholas II; Alex Shields
      Ben Lyon; 1904 automobile
      78: Charlie Chaplin; [remnants of
      79: John Kane; pupils at Isadora
      Duncan School, Moscow (1921); Harvest
      workers; dancers; Max Baer; Pocahontas
      Lodge meeting; native woman
      80: Alice Astor Pleydell-Bouverie with
      Tchelitchew portraits; Cecil Beaton
      GPL with Glenway Wescott, Jean
      Cocteau, and Cecil Beaton
      81: Sinking of the Vestris; Life magazine article on party given by
      Cecil Beaton [loose fragments stored
      with Separated Items]
      82: Helena Rubenstein with Pavel
      Tchelitchew portrait
      83: Fulco di Verdura; man standing on
      airplane propeller; [removed items:
      Photograph - Corot by Carjat
      Photograph - Unidentified man
      Photograph: Unidentified man]
      84: [Removed item: Photograph - Two
      nude young girls on bed]
      85: Image from Duke of Newcastle's
      "Méthode... nouvelle de dresser les
      Chevaux"; Greta Garbo; High Eagle,
      Blackfoot Indian chief; [removed item:
      Photograph - Two semi-nude men in
      wrestling pose]
      86: Sarah Bernhardt; Réjane; Cléo de
      Mérode; Hélène Petit; Cécile Sorel
      Marie Tempest; Anne Morgan; sons of
      Susuhunan of Surakurta; Henri
      Gaudier-Brzeska; Mrs. Kellogg Fairbank
    - Pages 87-98 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      87: Beatrice Lillie; statue of man
      88: Alexandre Dumas, père; George
      Sand; Victor Hugo; Gustave Doré
      fashion; Phil Scott; Madge Titheradge
      [removed items: Photograph - Man
      examining airplane propeller engine,
      stamped: "Courtesy of Pan American
      Airways"; Photograph - Group of ballet
      dancers (one male, two female) in
      rehearsal studio]
      89: [Removed item: Photograph - Group
      of topless women sunbathing]
      octagonal buildings; fashion
      90: [Removed item: Colored clipping -
      Self-portrait by Frida Kahlo]
      91: [Removed item: Photograph: Woman
      wearing mask and adorned with oysters,
      an eel and a lobster [costume by
      Dali?] by GPL]; Charles Trenet; Loie
      Fuller
      92: Unidentified woman
      93: Groups of boys showering; May
      Goelet; Cary Grant
      94: Group of athletes; Madame
      Cavalieri; fashion
      95: Group of athletes; electrical
      towers
      96: Male actors in female roles; Pavel
      Tchelitchew drawing of Natalie Paley
      97: Pavel Tchelitchew drawing of Esme
      O'Brian
      98: Painting: "Noonday Heat" by Henry
      S. Tuke; fashion; [removed item:
      Colored clipping - Painting by Pavel
    - Pages 99-104 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      99: [Removed item: Colored clipping -
      100: [Removed item: Colored clipping -
      "Cavalrymen Crossing a River", mural
      by Jared French]; monkey in water
      101: Woman playing cards; men on
      camels
      102: Prostrate man [possibly dead]
      "Afternoon on the Island", photograph
      by Rolf Tietjens
      103: Mrs. Allan A. Ryan; [removed
      item: Clipping - Illustration of woman
      in train car]
      104: blank
  - LOOSE SCRAPBOOK LEAVES
    - Loose pages with contact prints (Box 3, Folder 22)
      Ten pages of contact prints made
      by GPL and PAJAMA, See: Separated
      Items for description
    - Loose pages with clippings and photographs (Box 3, Folder 23)
      11 loose: Pavel Tchelitchew drawing
      Marlene Dietrich; Parisian painters
      (including Pavel Tchelitchew)
      11: Mae West by Hoyningen-Huene; man
      lifting bicycle; nude female models
      Paul Verlaine
      12: Fashion; Emmy Destin and Enrico
      Caruso; Queen Mary with Princess
      Adelaide and the Prince of Wales
      scenes from "Four Saints in Three
      Acts"
      13: Sitwell family portrait by
      Sargent; Edith Sitwell by Pavel
      Tchelitchew; [removed item:
      Photograph - Ornately decorated
      hallway with staircase]; man with
      hawks
      14: [Removed items: Carnival of
      Venice, See: Separated Items for
      description]
      15: Women wading in the sea; House
      remodeled by Durst; [removed item:
      Colored clipping: Model in front of
      backdrop by Pavel Tchelitchew]
      Gertrude Stein's apartment on the Rue
      De Fleurus
      16: "Der Springende Neger Bill"; Baron
      George Hoyningen-Huene by Beaton
      "Sudermann in St. Moritz"; Eulace
      Peacock; Joe Louis
      17: Lotte Lehman; group of people on a
      beach; Tamara Geva in "Errante"
      Gabriele d'Annunzio; Benga (dancer)
      18: Greta Garbo
  - ORIGINAL COVER BOARDS
    - Original cover boards (Box 4)
- Separated Items: Photographs and Color Images, ca. 1900-55; Series II; 0.84; (2 boxes)
  - VOLUME I
    - Colored clipping: monkey artist, Viki, with paintings (from: SI-2r) (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Photograph: Painting of two young boys reading, marked "Metropolitan Museum of Art" (from: SI-13r) (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Colored clipping: African boy in red costume (from: SI-17r) (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Colored clippings: Painting by Pavel Tchelitchew (from: SI-21r) (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Colored clipping: Painting by Pavel Tchelitchew (from: SI-23r) (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Colored clipping: Painting by Marc Chagall (from: SI-24v) (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Colored clippings: Photograph of Cecile Sorel (from: SI-26r) and Painting by Thomas Eakins (from: SI-26v) (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Colored clipping: Painting by Bougereau (from: SI-27v) (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Photograph: Ambroise Vollard by Brassai (from: SI-29v) (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - VOLUME II
    - Photograph: Boys playing baseball in urban lot (from: SII-1) (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Photograph: Unidentified man (from: SII-1) (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Photograph: Rear view of woman wearing open undergarments (from: SII-2) (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Photograph: Melka from the Folies Bergères (from: SII-2) (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Colored postcard: Nuestra Senora de Covadonga, addressed to GPL from Max [Ewing?], 1933 Dec 16 (from: SII-2) (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Colored postcard: "Scenes et types - jeune mauresque" (from: SII-2) (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Colored postcard: "Casablanca - jeune mauresque rêvant" (from: SII-2) (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Colored postcard: "Scenes et types - jeune Bédouine" (from: SII-2) (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Photograph, cabinet card: Offenbach by Carjat (from: SII-2) (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Color clipping: Photograph of Max Baer by Breuhl-Bourges, Vanity Fair, 1934 Sep (from SII-4) (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Photograph: Nude female with fan (from SII-7) (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Photograph: Group of young men in bathhouse or grotto (from: SII-8) (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Photographs: Two different prints of Oriental men in military or ceremonial costumes (from: SII-11) (Box 5, Folder 45-46)
    - Photograph: Bearded man in workshop (from: SII-11) (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Photograph: Nude woman posed in front of theatrical backdrop holding dagger [from: SII-11] (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Photographs: Three sheets with multiple poses of nude young men and a nude woman with a child (from: SII-12) (Box 5, Folder 49-51)
    - Photographs: Four sheets with multiple poses of semi-nude muscular men (the Ritter brothers) (from: SII-12) (Box 5, Folder 52-55)
    - Photographic postcard: Offenbach by Nadar (from: SII-13) (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Photographic postcard: Gertrude Stein and Alice Toklas with Ford truck in Rivesaltes, France in front of birthplace of Marshall Joffre (1917 Apr) (SII-13) (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Photographic postcard: Corot by Nadar, addressed to Miss F. M. Cottenet (from: SII-13) (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Photographic postcard: Margarete Preuse-Matzenauer addressed to GPL by Tonio [Selwart?], [1932 Apr 19?] (from: SII-13) (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Postcard: Lois Moran, addressed to GPL by Max [Ewing?], 1933 Aug 2 (from: SII-13) (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Postcard: Tinted image of young man holding flowers (from: SII-13) (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Photographic postcard: Feral Bengal, Folies Bergères (from: SII-13) (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Postcard: Maroc (Scénes et types) - Marocain préparant le thé (from: SII-13) (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Photographic postcard: Feral Bengal, Folies Bergère (from: SII-13) (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Photograph: Unidentified woman in fur hat and coat (from: SII-14) (Box 5, Folder 65)
      Same as: SII-33
    - Photograph: Unidentified man in fur hat and coat (from: SII-14) (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Photograph: Nude young man posing under tropical plant (from: SII-14) (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - Photograph: George Sand (from: SII-15) (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Photographs: Two different shots of woman in traditional Chinese costumes (from: SII-17) (Box 5, Folder 69-70)
    - Photographic postcard: Two dance pupils in the Zurich Theater, addressed to GPL from [Lenjoi?] (from: SII-23) (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - Colored clipping: Jimmy Daniels with dancers (from: SII-23) (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Photograph: Two oriental men posing in simple clothing (from: SII-25) (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - Photograph: Woman posing with bracelets and shawl (from: SII-26) (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - Photographic postcard: Head of a burro (from: SII-31) (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - Photographs: Johnny Weismuller in four poses: one as Tarzan and three aboard a sailboat (from: SII-32) (Box 5, Folder 76-79)
    - Photographs: Two poses of man and woman in fur hats and coats (from: SII-33) (Box 5, Folder 80-81)
      Same as: SII-14
    - Photograph: Nude young girl posing with tambourine painted with portrait of a young man (from: SII-38) (Box 5, Folder 82)
    - Photograph: Sheet with multiple shots of young women in various poses, by Nadar (from: SII-44) (Box 5, Folder 83)
    - Photographs: Two different face shots of Marlene Dietrich (from: SII-48) (Box 5, Folder 84-85)
    - Photographic postcard: Two male athletes: "Partnerubung: Waage" by Siegfried Dietrich (from: SII-49) (Box 5, Folder 86)
    - Photographic postcard, colored: nude woman on chairs by window (from: SII-49) (Box 5, Folder 87)
    - Postcard: Mary Pickford in "Tess of the Storm Country", addressed to GPL by Max [Ewing?], 1933 Sep 5 (from: SII-49) (Box 5, Folder 88)
    - Postcard: "Scénes et types: Fatma dans sa intérieur (from: SII-49) (Box 5, Folder 89)
    - Postcard: "Riatia sous la douche" (from: SII-49) (Box 5, Folder 90)
    - Colored clipping: Model wearing large hat - with butterfly pasted on image (from: SII-56) (Box 5, Folder 91)
    - Photograph: Nude young black woman (from: SII-58) (Box 5, Folder 92)
    - Photographs: Seven candid shots of men playing water polo (from: SII-58 & 59) (Box 5, Folder 93-99)
    - Colored clippings: "Plaisances et Rocailles par Jean Hugo" (from: SII-60 & 61) (Box 5, Folder 100-101)
    - Colored clipping: fashion shot with woman admiring herself in handheld mirror, in front of backdrop by Pavel Tchelitchew (from: SII-62) (Box 5, Folder 102)
    - Photographs: Three separate portraits of unidentified man (from: SII-64) (Box 5, Folder 103-105)
    - Photographic postcards: Two views of matadors in action, one identified as "Armillita" (from: loose between SII-64 & 65) (Box 5, Folder 106-107)
    - Photographic postcards: Three views of matadors, two identified as "Serna" and "Ortega", (from: SII-65) (Box 5, Folder 108-110)
    - Colored clipping: Fashion illustration by Vertes (from: SII-69) (Box 6, Folder 111)
    - Photographs: Set illustrations [by Pavel Tchelitchew?] (from: SII-70 & 71) (Box 6, Folder 112-115)
    - Photographs: Costume illustrations [by Pavel Tchelitchew?] (from: SII- 72, 73, & 74) (Box 6, Folder 116-135)
    - Colored clipping: Nude girl carrying, with separate decorative pasted over as border (from: SII-76) (Box 6, Folder 136)
    - Loose fragments from: SIII-81 (Box 6, Folder 137)
    - Photograph: Corot by Carjat (from: SII-83) (Box 6, Folder 138)
    - Photograph: Unidentified man (from: SII-83) (Box 6, Folder 139)
    - Photograph: Unidentified man (from: SII-83) (Box 6, Folder 140)
    - Photograph: Two nude young girls on bed (from: SII-84) (Box 6, Folder 141)
    - Photograph: Two semi-nude men in wrestling pose (from: SII-85) (Box 6, Folder 142)
    - Photograph: Man examining airplane propeller engine, stamped: "Courtesy of Pan American Airways"(from: SII-88) (Box 6, Folder 143)
    - Photograph: Group of ballet dancers (one male, two female) in rehearsal studio (from: SII-88) (Box 6, Folder 144)
    - Photograph: Group of topless women sunbathing (from: SII-89) (Box 6, Folder 145)
    - Colored clipping: Self-portrait by Frida Kahlo (from: SII-90) (Box 6, Folder 146)
    - Photograph: Woman wearing mask and adorned with oysters, an eel and a lobster [costume by Dali?] by GPL (from: SII-91) (Box 6, Folder 147)
    - Colored clippings: Two paintings by Pavel Tchelitchew (from: SII-98 & 99) (Box 6, Folder 148-149)
    - Colored clipping: "Cavalrymen Crossing a River", mural by Jared French (from: SII-100) (Box 6, Folder 150)
    - Clipping: Illustration of woman in train car (from: SII-103) (Box 6, Folder 151)
  - LOOSE SCRAPBOOK LEAVES
    - Photographs: Twenty contact prints from page labeled: "Mrs. Lawrence Lowman and GPL, New York, Sept. 10 [year missing]" (Box 6, Folder 152)
    - Photographs: Fourteen contact prints from page labeled: "Paul Cadmus, Fire Island, Sept. 1941." (Box 6, Folder 153)
    - Photographs: Twenty contact prints from page labeled: "Katharine Anne Porter, South Hill, Saratoga Springs, Aug. 194[?]" (Box 6, Folder 154)
    - Photographs: Ten contact prints from page labeled: "Barbara and Lloyd Wescott and M.W. [Monroe Wheeler] - Mulhocaway Farm, Clinton, N.J. Sept. 1941, Flemington Fair, Sept. 1941" (Box 6, Folder 155)
    - Photographs: Ten contact prints from page labeled: Adelaide Sparkman Lynes, North Egremont, Aug. 1941, K.A.P. and M.W. [Katharine Anne Porter and Monroe Wheeler] (Box 6, Folder 156)
    - Photographs: Eighteen contact prints from page labeled: "G.P.L. - Paul Cadmus and Margaret French, Fire Island, Sept. 194[?]" (Box 6, Folder 157)
    - Photographs: Six contact prints from unlabeled page: Somerset Maugham reclining on couch, reading (Box 6, Folder 158)
    - Photographs: Four contact prints from unlabeled page: Jared French sketching Monroe Wheeler (Box 6, Folder 159)
    - Photographs: Three contact prints from unlabeled page: Glenway Wescott reading newspaper and standing in kitchen (Box 6, Folder 160)
    - Photograph: One contact print from unlabeled page: Monroe Wheeler lying in bed (Box 6, Folder 161)
    - Photograph: Ornately decorated hallway with staircase (Box 6, Folder 162)
    - Photographs: Twenty-six shots of men and women posed individually and together in front of Max Ewing's "Carnival of Venice" backdrop (Box 6, Folder 163)
      Indentified people include:
      Lloyd Wescott
      Dorothy Crawford
      Paul Meeres
      Muriel Draper
      Paul Robison
      Max Ewing
      Lincoln Kirstein
      Dorothy Sheldon
      GPL
    - Colored clipping: Model in front of backdrop by Pavel Tchelitchew (Box 6, Folder 164)